# **Ziaul Islam** Sector 17, Gurgaon, India

## ziaul.engg@gmail.com 9957081762

**Summary** 

I am an M Tech CSE graduated IT professional having 3+ years of project management experience in end to end implementation of large scale web based integrated payment processing system & compliance software solution. I have extensive understanding of Accounting and Financial processes of both central and state government departments & their agencies, Regulatory Compliance in Central KYC and Anti Money Laundering screening for BFSI industries.

## **Skills & Expertise**

Project Management: Project Scope, Timeline, Planning, Execution, Resource allocation, Gap analysis, Risk analysis, Monitoring Problem solving, Decision making, SDLC, Agile, Scrum

Change Management: Analysis of organization's hierarchy, components, fund flow. Architect workflow, flow chart, product implementation roadmap, impact analysis

Business Analysis: Business domain analysis, Business process analysis, Documentation of Business & System requirements, User stories, Use cases, DFD, Decision table

Data Analysis: Quantitative and Qualitative Data analysis, Data reconciliation, Data Extraction, Data warehousing, Observation of data in application and database

Training and Solution: Presentation, End user training, New joinee training, documentation of User Manual, SOP. Solution to the issues & end user queries

Integration: Data integration, Image integration, Data modelling, data mapping, Data vault, Web Services API integration, System integration

Quality Control: Identify and preparation test scenarios, Test Cases, User acceptance testing, Use case testing, Corner case testing, Black box & white box testing

Tools and Technologies: MS Excel, PowerPoint, Spreadsheets, SharePoints, Tableau, JIRA, Atlassian Confluence, JIRA Service Desk, Core Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, SQL, OLAP, Oracle Flexcube, MS SQL Server, AWS RDS, Windows RDP, Postman, JSON, WinSCP, SFTP, Arcoss privileged access management, SFTP, FTP, Draw.io

### **Experience, Education, Certification & Training**

### Experience

- TSS Consultancy Pvt Ltd (product based company), 1st February 2019 to Present (under payroll of TeamLease)
- SRIT India Pvt Ltd (CMMI Level 5 Company), 7<sup>th</sup> September 2016 to 30<sup>th</sup> December 2018

### **Education**

- M.Tech CSE from Gauhati University, 2012-2014
- MCA from Dibrugarh University, 2009-2012
- B.Sc from Gauhati University, 2006-2009

## Certification

Tally Financial and Accounting Certification (TFAC)

# **Training**

Automation of Calibration Laboratory at Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR), Chennai, 5 months

## **Project Details**

#1 Project Title: AML (Anti Money Laundering) screening

**Duration:** 1<sup>st</sup> August 2019 to Present Client: Car24 Financial Services Company: TSS Consultancy Pvt Ltd

Technologies: SQL, SQL Server, AWS RDS, JIRA, Atlassian Confluence, MS Excel, Spreadsheet, Power Point, SharePoint, SDLC,

Trackwizz

**Role:** Business Analyst

# Responsibility:

- Interact with client to understand their problems and needs
- Gather the requirements and documents them
- Analyse the requirements, propose the solution and freeze requirements
- Test case preparation and passing on requirements to the technical team
- Ensure system meets the requirements
- Process design to standardize the organization's workflow
- Support during implementation
- AML screening rules writing and design screening matrices
- Proposing new AML Screening algorithms

#2 Project Title: CKYC (Central Know Your Customer)

**Duration:** 1st February 2019 to 31st July 2019

Client: Airtel Payments Bank & IFFCO Tokio General Insurance

Company: TSS Consultancy Pvt Ltd

**Technologies:** SQL, Microsoft SQL Server 2014, Oracle Flexcube, Arcoss privileged access management, Windows RDP, Web Services API, JSON, XML, Postman, FTP, SFTP, JIRA, Atlassian Confluence, JIRA Service Desk Spreadsheet, Power Point, Draw.io,

SDLC, Trackwizz

Role: Assistant Project Manager

### Responsibility:

- Project planning, Execution, Monitoring and Controlling
- Client engagement on business & IT solution
- Functional and Non Functional requirements gathering and documentation
- Business process redesign
- Proposed business solution
- Algorithm design and analysis
- Ensure Quality Controls and User Acceptance Testing
- Support in Solution Deployment and system configuration
- Support in Web Service API implementation with Siebel CRM & Pega CRM
- System integration with CKYC Registry
- Integration of Data & Images, Data mapping, Data Vault with Oracle Flexcube & MS SQL Server
- Data monitoring and evaluation
- Training, Workshop, Presentation, SOP, User manual, End user queries, Issue tracking and solution

#3 Project Title: PFMS (Public Financial Management System)

**Duration:** 7<sup>th</sup> September 2016 to 30<sup>th</sup> December 2018

Client: Controller General of Accounts- Ministry of Finance, New Delhi

Company: SRIT India Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Technologies: Core Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, SQL, Web Services, OLAP, SQL Server, XML, Microsoft BitzTalk, FTP, SFTP,

SharePoint, Tableau, MS Excel, PowerPoint, SDLC, Cacoo, PFMS,

Role: Sr. Project Management Associate

## Responsibility:

- Coordination with Project Teams, Stakeholders.
- Liaison with Public & Private sector banks.
- Analysis and architect organization's fund flow, hierarchy, components.
- Gap analysis, Risk assessment
- Support in Application Integration with different external systems
- Assisting on Data modelling, data warehousing, data extraction, data reconciliation
- Configuration workflows and Functional mapping of agencies
- User Acceptance Testing
- Monitoring and analyzing data
- Identifying issues and provide solutions
- Training to end users & User manual preparation
- Designing new innovative ideas on problem solving